Sasha Weiss (Alexander)

(773) 896 7224 sashaweiss.coffee sasha@sashaweiss.coffee

Computer Science student at Northwestern University, graduating in June with a B.S. + M.S. Two industry internships and significant HCI research experience, focused on building technology to *make things easier*. Quick and open learner, big on automation and thorough testing. Ex-ballet dancer, speaks French, and loves Star Wars.

EXPERIENCE

Braintree Payments, San Francisco — Software Engineering Intern

June 2017 - September 2017

Developed a tool to automatically generate developer-facing SDKs for RESTful APIs, targeting Java, Python, Node.js, and Ruby, written with Go and Docker. **Built automated testing** verifying correctness of generated code. **Wrote extensive documentation** in preparation for internal and external deployment, and imminent open-sourcing.

HERE Maps, Chicago — Software Engineering Intern

June 2016 - September 2016

Designed and built a library supporting custom indexing into map datastores, using Scala and Docker. **Deployed to internal production** environments, reducing processing time of my team's products by between ~2 and ~50x. **Wrote extensive documentation** to allow easy integration by other teams.

Delta Lab, Northwestern University — *Undergraduate Researcher*

March 2016 - Present

Researching how context-sensing and microreminding techniques can support long-term behavior change. **Building prototype iOS reminder systems** and evaluating via iterative deployments. **Conducting interviews** and collating evidence, and **writing manuscripts**.

EECS Department, Northwestern University — Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

January 2016 - Present

Leading tutorial sessions and office hours for 400+ students/quarter in introductory CS courses. **Teaching students** computer science and software development principles in C++, Python, and Racket.

EDUCATION LANGUAGES AND TOOLS

Northwestern University - B.S./M.S., GPA 3.89/4.00

June 2018 (anticipated)

Notable courses: Design, Technology, and Research (DTR), Human-Computer Interaction, Compiler Construction, Operating Systems, Programming Languages, Communication Networks, Statistical Language Modeling, Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Theory of Computation TypeScript, Python, Node.js, Swift (iOS)
Unix, Git, Vim, tmux, TDD, Agile, REST

Familiar

Proficient

Go, C++, Scala, HTML/CSS, Ruby, Java Docker, Gradle, Rake, Gulp, Puppet

PROJECTS

Parcheesi Player (TypeScript): - a networked AI for playing round robin Parcheesi matches. **Hephaestus (iOS Swift, Firebase)** - a smart reminder system supporting habit-building. **LC Compiler (C++)** - a multi-pass, modular compiler targeting a subset of C. **WhichProf? (Python, HTML)** - a system matching your voice to the closest EECS professor.